<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><MiramoXML xmlns:miramo="http://ExternalFunction.miramo.com" xmlns:mm="http://www.miramo.com/XSL/Transform" language="usEnglish"><!--DOCMAP--><VarDef varDef="lang-appendix">Appendix </VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-chapter">Chapter </VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-table">Table </VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-figure">Figure </VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-page">page</VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-onpage"> on page </VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-index">Index</VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-contents">Contents</VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-preface">Preface</VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-notice">Notice</VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-related">Related Links</VarDef><VarDef varDef="printDate"><Date dateDef="lmdate"/></VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-prereq">Before you begin</VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-postreq">What to do next</VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-example">Example</VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-context">About this task</VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-procedure">Procedure</VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-procedure-unordered">Procedure</VarDef><VarDef varDef="lang-results">Results</VarDef><TblContinuationDef tblContinuationDef="figure"> (continued)</TblContinuationDef><!--opentopic:map outputclass=docmap parent@outputclass=[]--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[mmpdf:section:firstSection]--><Section sectionDef="firstSection"/><!--DOC ignoring text 
    --><VarDef varDef="mainbooktitle">DITA Project 2 - Michael Sweeney</VarDef><MetaData name="title">DITA Project 2 - Michael Sweeney</MetaData><!--DOC ignoring text 
    --><!--map/topicref --><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--MAP/TOPICREF (doc)d2e12--><!--DOC ignoring text 
    --><!--map/topicref --><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--MAP/TOPICREF (doc)unique_1--><!--topic/title parent concept count= outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title"><MkDest id="#unique_1"/>About this publication</P>
        <P paraDef="body"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [i] id=--><Font fontDef="i">IBM StoredIQ Deployment and Configuration Guide</Font> provides information about how to plan, deploy, and
            configure the IBM StoredIQ product.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=1 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title1"><MkDest id="#unique_2"/>IBM StoredIQ product library</P>
        <P paraDef="body">The following documents are available in the IBM® StoredIQ® product library.</P>
        
            <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [i] id=--><Font fontDef="i">IBM StoredIQ Overview Guide</Font></P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [i] id=--><Font fontDef="i">IBM StoredIQ Deployment and Configuration on Guide</Font></P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [i] id=--><Font fontDef="i">IBM StoredIQ Data Server Administration Guide</Font></P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [i] id=--><Font fontDef="i">IBM StoredIQ Administrator Administration Guide</Font></P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [i] id=--><Font fontDef="i">IBM StoredIQ Data Workbench User Guide</Font></P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [i] id=--><Font fontDef="i">IBM StoredIQ Policy Manager User Guide</Font></P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [i] id=--><Font fontDef="i">IBM StoredIQ Insights User Guide</Font></P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [i] id=--><Font fontDef="i">IBM StoredIQ Integration Guide</Font></P>
            </ParaGroup>
        
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=1 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title1"><MkDest id="#unique_3"/>Contacting IBM StoredIQ customer support</P>
        <P paraDef="body">For IBM StoredIQ technical support or to learn about available service options, contact IBM StoredIQ
            customer support at this phone number:</P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">1-866-227-2068</P>
        </ParaGroup>
        <P paraDef="body">Or, see the Contact IBM web site at <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [u] id=--><Font fontDef="u"><HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="http://www.ibm.com/contact/us/">http://www.ibm.com/contact/us/</HyperCmd></Font></P>
        
        <P paraDef="body"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">IBM Knowledge Center</Font></P>
        <P paraDef="body">The IBM StoredIQ documentation is available in <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [u] id=--><Font fontDef="u"><HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/knowledgecenter/">IBM Knowledge Center</HyperCmd></Font>.</P>
           
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_4"/>Contacting IBM</P>
        <P paraDef="body">For general inquiries, call 800-IBM-4YOU (800-426-4968). To contact IBM customer service in the
            United States or Canada, call 1-800-IBM-SERV (1-800-426-7378).</P>
            <P paraDef="body">For more information about how to contact IBM, including TTY service, see the Contact
            IBM website at <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [u] id=--><Font fontDef="u"><HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="http://www.ibm.com/contact/us/">http://www.ibm.com/contact/us/</HyperCmd></Font>. </P>
    <!--DOC ignoring text 
    --><!--map/topicref --><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--MAP/TOPICREF (doc)unique_5--><!--topic/title parent concept count= outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title"><MkDest id="#unique_5"/>IBM StoredIQ components</P>
        <P paraDef="body">The IBM StoredIQ solution consists of these components: the application stack, the gateway, the data
            server, and optionally the Elasticsearch cluster</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=1 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title1"><MkDest id="#unique_6"/>Solution components</P>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ provides three solution components: the gateway, data servers, and application stack
            (AppStack).</P>
        
        <P paraDef="body"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Gateway</Font></P>
        <P paraDef="body">The gateway communicates between the data servers and the application stack. The application stack
            polls the gateway for information about the data on the data servers. The data servers push the
            information to the gateway.</P>
        
            <P paraDef="body"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Data servers</Font></P>
        <P paraDef="body">A data server obtains the data from supported data sources and indexes it. By indexing this data, you
            gain information about unstructured data such as file size, file data types, file owners.</P>
        
            <P paraDef="body">The data server pushes the information about volumes and indexes to the gateway so it can be
                communicated to the application stack. Multiple data servers feed into a single gateway.</P>
        
            <P paraDef="body">Data servers can be categorized in two types: DataServer - Classic and DataServer - Distributed. A
            data server of the type DataServer - Classic uses the embedded PostgreSQL database for storing the
            index. With a data server of the type DataServer - Distributed, the index is stored in an Elasticsearch
            cluster. Data servers of this type also provide better performance in search queries. They can manage
            much larger amounts of data than data servers of the type DataServer - Classic, thus making the IBM
            StoredIQ deployments more scalable.</P>
        
        <P paraDef="body">You can have both types of data servers in your IBM StoredIQ deployment.</P>
        
            <P paraDef="body">In addition to completing standard administrative tasks, administrators can deploy the IBM StoredIQ
            Desktop Data Collector and index desktops from the data server.</P>
        
        <P paraDef="body"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Application stack</Font></P>
            <P paraDef="body">The application stack provides the user interface for the IBM StoredIQ Administrator, IBM StoredIQ
                Data Workbench, IBM StoredIQ Insights, and the IBM StoredIQ Policy Manager products.</P>
        
            <P paraDef="body">The synchronization feature for integration with a governance catalog is also part of the application
                stack.</P>
        
        <P paraDef="body"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Elasticsearch cluster</Font></P>
            <P paraDef="body">The Elasticsearch cluster attached to a data server of the type DataServer - Distributed provides a
            single data store for all metadata and content of harvested objects. Indexed data is distributed
            automatically across the nodes in the cluster. Indexing and queries are load-balanced across all
            nodes. Nodes can be added dynamically without downtime and the indexing process can use these
            newly added nodes without further setup.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=1 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title1"><MkDest id="#unique_7"/>Applications of IBM StoredIQ</P>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ provides interface applications that help fulfill its solution goals.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_8"/>IBM StoredIQ Data Server</P>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ Data Server user interface provides access to data server functionality. It
            allows administrators to view the dashboard and see the status of the jobs and system
            details. Administrators can manage information about servers and conduct various
            configurations on the system and application settings. </P>
        <AFrame wrap="Y" position="inline" crop="N" startIndent="inherit" align="start"><!--makeImage 0--><Image file="images/ibm1.PNG" width="750px" keepAspectRatio="Y"/></AFrame>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_9"/>IBM StoredIQ Administrator</P>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ Administrator helps you manage global assets common to the distributed infrastructure
            behind IBM StoredIQ applications.</P>
        <AFrame wrap="Y" position="inline" crop="N" startIndent="inherit" align="start"><!--makeImage 0--><Image file="images/ibm2.PNG" width="750px" keepAspectRatio="Y"/></AFrame>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ Administrator provides at-a-glance understanding of the different issues that can crop up
            in the IBM StoredIQ environment. These views are unique to the IBM StoredIQ Administrator application
            as they provide an overview of how the system is running. They allow access to various pieces of
            information that are being shared across applications or allow for the management of resources in a
            centralized manner.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">The administrator is the person responsible for managing the IBM StoredIQ. This individual has strong
            understanding of data sources, indexes, data servers, jobs, infosets, and actions. This list provides an
            overview as to how IBM StoredIQ Administrator works:</P>
        
            <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
                <!--topic/li-->
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Viewing data servers and volumes:</Font> Using IBM StoredIQ Administrator, the Administrator can identify
                    what data servers are deployed, their location, what data is being managed, and the status of each data
                    server in the system. Volume management is a central component of IBM StoredIQ. IBM StoredIQ
                    Administrator also allows the Administrator to see what volumes are currently under management,
                    which data server is responsible for that volume, the state of the volume after indexing, and the amount
                    and size of information that is contained by each volume. Administrators can also add volumes to and
                    delete volumes from data servers through this interface.</P>
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" listLabel="N" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">If IBM StoredIQ is configured for integration with Information Governance Catalog, the Administrator
                        can also manage which volumes are published to the governance catalog.</P>
                
                <!--topic/li-->
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Scheduling harvests:</Font> Harvesting, which can also be referred to as indexing, is the process or task by
                    which IBM StoredIQ examines and classifies data in your network. Using IBM StoredIQ Administrator,
                    harvests can be scheduled, edited, and deleted.</P>
                
                <!--topic/li-->
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Creating system infosets:</Font> System infosets that use only speci³c indexed volumes can be created and
                        managed within IBM StoredIQ Administrator. Although infosets are a core component of IBM StoredIQ
                        Data Workbench, system infosets are created as a shortcut for users in IBM StoredIQ Administrator.</P>
                
                <!--topic/li-->
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Managing users:</Font> The user management area allows administrators to create users and manage users'
                        access to the various IBM StoredIQ applications</P>
                
                <!--topic/li-->
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Configuration and managing actions:</Font> An action is any process that is taken upon the data that is
                        represented by the indexes. Actions are run by data servers on indexed data objects. Any errors or
                        warnings that are generated as a result of an action are recorded as exceptions in IBM StoredIQ Data
                        Workbench.</P>
                    <P paraDef="note"><ListLabel><Image file="M:\build-tools\note-images/note.svg" top="-1mm"/></ListLabel><Font fontDef="notetext">Note: </Font>Actions can be created within IBM StoredIQ Administrator and then made available to other IBM
                        StoredIQ applications such as IBM StoredIQ Data Workbench.</P>
                
                <!--topic/li-->
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Managing target sets:</Font> Provides an interface that allows the user to set the wanted targets for speci³c
                        actions that require a destination volume for their actions.</P>
                
                <!--topic/li-->
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Report:</Font> IBM StoredIQ Administrator provides a number of built-in reports, such as summaries of data
                        objects in the system, storage use, and the number of identical documents in the system. You can
                        create custom reports, including Query Analysis Reports for e-discovery purposes, and automatically
                        email report notifications to administrators and other interested parties.</P>
                
                <!--topic/li-->
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Auto-classification:</Font> Automated document categorization, what IBM StoredIQ refers to as auto-classification
                        models, integrates the IBM® Content Classification's classification model into the IBM
                        StoredIQ infoset-generation process. Data Experts can use IBM Content Classification to train a
                        classication model, which is then registered with IBM StoredIQ Administrator. The registered
                        classication model can be applied to an existing infoset in IBM StoredIQ Data Workbench to generate
                        new metadata for the objects in the infoset. Metadata can be used in rule-based filters to create new
                        infosets.</P>
                
                <!--topic/li-->
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Cartridges:</Font> Cartridges are compressed files that contain analysis logic. When you add a cartridge to
                        IBM StoredIQ AppStack, it can detect new data in documents during indexing and make these new
                        insights searchable. For example, a sensitive pattern cartridge can enable IBM StoredIQ to detect
                        passport numbers, phone numbers, and other IDs</P>
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" listLabel="N">To apply the analysis logic contained in the cartridge, you must run a Step-up Analytics action that uses
                        the cartridge on an infoset. IBM StoredIQ examines all documents in the infoset, applies the analytics,
                        and then stores the analysis results in the IBM StoredIQ index</P>
                
                <!--topic/li-->
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Managing concepts:</Font> Provides the ability to relate business concepts to indexed data</P>
                
                <!--topic/li-->
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Managing Mule scripts:</Font> Helps you to create Mule scripts and upload script packages. These Mule
                        scripts are used by IBM StoredIQ Policy Manager to create policies using the automation workflow</P>
                
                <!--topic/li-->
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">DataServer - Classic:</Font> Data servers can be categorized in two types: DataServer - Classic and
                        DataServer - Distributed. DataServer - Classic refers to the regular data servers. It uses either the
                        current PostgreSQL or Lucene index as an index</P>
                
                <!--topic/li-->
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">DataServer - Distributed</Font> The distributed data server uses an Elasticsearch cluster instead of an
                        embedded Postgres database. It increases the scalability and flexibility of the IBM StoredIQ
                        deployment in a way that it can manage much larger amounts of data. Without adding more data
                        servers, data that is managed by the IBM StoredIQ deployment can be increased by adding new nodes
                        to the Elasticsearch cluster. Search queries perform better on DataServer - Distributed.</P>
                
                <!--topic/li-->
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Connector API SDK:</Font> A connector is a software component of IBM StoredIQ that is used to connect to a
                        data source such as a network file system and access its data. Using IBM StoredIQ Connector API SDK,
                        developers of other companies can develop connectors to new data sources outside the IBM StoredIQ
                        development environment. These connectors can be integrated with a live IBM StoredIQ application to
                        index, search, manage, and analyze data on the data source.</P>
                
            </ParaGroup>
        
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_10"/>IBM StoredIQ Data Workbench</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Big data is a pervasive problem, not a one-time occurrence. It is easy for most companies
            to realize that big data is problematic, but it is hard to identify what problems they
            have. Big data is all about the unknown, but the unknown cannot be off limits. IBM
            StoredIQ Data Workbench can help you learn about your data, make educated decisions with
            your most valuable asset, and turn your company's most dangerous risk into its most
            valuable asset.</P>
        <AFrame wrap="Y" position="inline" crop="N" startIndent="inherit" align="start"><!--makeImage 0--><Image file="images/ibm3.PNG" width="750px" keepAspectRatio="Y"/></AFrame>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ Data Workbench is a data visualization and management tool that helps you to actively
            manage your company's data. It helps you to determine how much data you have, where it is, who owns
            it, and when it was last used. When you have a clear understanding of your company's data landscape,
            IBM StoredIQ Data Workbench helps you take control of data. You can make informed decisions about
            your data and act on that knowledge by copying, copying to retention, or conducting a discovery export.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Here are just some examples of how you can use IBM StoredIQ Data Workbench.</P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">You need to find all company email that is sent from or received by Eileen Sideways
                (esideways@thecompany.com). You can use IBM StoredIQ Data Workbench to find all email and then
                copy that data to a predefined repository. You can also use IBM StoredIQ Data Workbench to find all of
                the esideways@thecompany.com email that occurred between specific dates and then make that email
                available for review</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">As an administrator, you want to rid your networks and storage of unused data. You can use IBM
                StoredIQ Data Workbench to find all files that were not modified in more than five years.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">You want to find all image files that are created in 2007. Not only can IBM StoredIQ Data Workbench
                find all image files that were created in 2007. It also shows how much space they occupy on your
                network.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">A user needs to understand how data about Windows is being retained. Using IBM StoredIQ Data
                Workbench, you can provide that user with a visual overview of the number of objects that are retained
                and a breakdown of files per data source. Additionally, you can apply overlays to show the user if those
                files contain forbidden information such as credit-card numbers or Social Security numbers.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">If IBM StoredIQ is configured accordingly, you can select the infosets and filters that are published to
                the governance catalog for uni³ed governance of structured and unstructured information. When
                integrating with Information Governance Catalog, you can also analyze and classify the data governed
                by IBM StoredIQ based on the data classes that are synchronized from the governance catalog.</P>
        </ParaGroup>
           
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_11"/>IBM StoredIQ Insights</P>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ Insights provides dynamic and interactive filtering for your data with easy access to all
            metadata and instant plain-text preview of document content for full-text indexed volumes.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Faceted search lets you drill down to refine your search results as needed. In addition, you can apply any
            valid IBM StoredIQ filter query. Tags let you categorize the data for easier management. Visual
            representations of search results help you gain further insights into your data. Several chart types let you
            look at and explore data from different perspectives, thus helping you identify patterns and relationships
            very quickly.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">With IBM StoredIQ Insights, you can search data that is managed and indexed by a data server of the type
            DataServer - Distributed. In mixed deployments that have classic and distributed data servers, only the
            content from distributed data servers will be searchable.</P>
        <AFrame wrap="Y" position="inline" crop="N" startIndent="inherit" align="start"><!--makeImage 0--><Image file="images/ibm4.PNG" width="750px" keepAspectRatio="Y"/></AFrame>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_12"/>IBM StoredIQ Policy Manager</P>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ Policy Manager allows users to run mature policies and processes at scale across a wider
            range of data.</P>
        <AFrame wrap="Y" position="inline" crop="N" startIndent="inherit" align="start"><!--makeImage 0--><Image file="images/ibm5.PNG" width="750px" keepAspectRatio="Y"/></AFrame>
        <P paraDef="body">The users can define and run systemwide policies, focusing on the execution of the process rather than
            understanding or reviewing affected data objects. Additionally, with reports of IBM StoredIQ Policy
            Manager, you can record what actions were conducted, when they were conducted, and what data was
            affected by the policy's execution.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_13"/>IBM StoredIQ Desktop Data Collector</P>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ Desktop Data Collector (also referred to as desktop client) indexes desktops
            as volumes. The volumes appear in IBM StoredIQ Data Server and in IBM StoredIQ
            Administrator, where they can be used like any other data source.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">The data server maintains an index using the information sent by the desktop client. After indexing,
            desktops - even offline or unreachable ones - can be viewed, searched, or targeted for later policy action.</P>
    <!--DOC ignoring text 
    --><!--map/topicref --><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--MAP/TOPICREF (doc)unique_14--><!--topic/title parent concept count= outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title"><MkDest id="#unique_14"/>Planning for deployment</P>
        <P paraDef="body">When you plan a deployment of IBM StoredIQ, evaluate several infrastructure considerations.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">In addition to the information in this section, review the requirements detailed in the
            IBM Software Product Compatibility Reports (SPCR) tool at: <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/software/reports/compatibility/clarity-reports/report/html/softwareReqsForProduct?deliverableId=CC1291B0F4AF11E3ACBD4447721DA353">Software Product Compatibility Reports: StoredIQ
                7.6</HyperCmd></P>
        <P paraDef="body">If you plan to use IBM StoredIQ for Legal Identification and Collection to create and
            manage data boxes and data requests that are to be fulfilled by IBM StoredIQ, also check
            the system requirements for <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/software/reports/compatibility/clarity-reports/report/html/softwareReqsForProduct?deliverableId=8A0331A0C50D11E58D9C0D684F363D68">StoredIQ for Legal at: Software Product Compatibility
                Reports: StoredIQ for Legal 2.0.3</HyperCmd></P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=1 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title1"><MkDest id="#unique_15"/>Generate customized reports with the SPCR tool</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Go to the page at <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/software/reports/compatibility/clarity/index.html">Software Product Compatibility Reports</HyperCmd> to
            create a high-level report for supported operating systems, related software,
            hypervisors, and supported translations for any product. You can also create an in-depth
            report to get detailed system requirements, hardware requirements, and end of service
            information for each product. You can search for a product in all of the report types
            and reports are generated based on your query values.</P>
            <P paraDef="body">The following report types are the most commonly generated reports from software product compatibility
            reports:</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_16"/>Detailed system requirements</P>
        <P paraDef="body">When you select your product version for the detailed system requirements report, you can set a
            report filter for <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Operating system platforms</Font>, <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Product components</Font>, and <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Capabilities</Font>, including
            prerequisites and support software. After you view the report, you can save it as a URL to generate
            anytime or download it as a PDF.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_17"/>Hardware requirements</P>
        <P paraDef="body">When you select your product version for the hardware requirements report, you can set a report filter
            by the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Operating system families</Font> option. Set the operating system filter by selecting some or all of
            the operating systems that are supported by your product. After you view the report, you can save it
            as a URL to generate anytime or download it as a PDF.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_18"/>End of service</P>
        <P paraDef="body">The end of service report shows the service window of the products that you specify over
            an eightyear span. For example, you can find out when your product is scheduled to go
            out of service.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=1 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title1"><MkDest id="#unique_19"/>Open Virtual Appliance (OVA) configuration requirements</P>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ is deployed as virtual appliances and is supported in VMware ESXi 5.0 (all fix pack levels) or
            VMware ESXi 6.0 (all fix pack levels) environments. You must have a virtual infrastructure that meets the
            IBM StoredIQ hardware requirements.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_20"/>Application stack</P>
        
            <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">vCPU: 2</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Memory: 4 GB</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Storage:
                <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul_ul">
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">Primary disk (vmdisk1): 21 GB</P>
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">Data disk (vmdisk2): 10 GB</P>
                </ParaGroup></P>
        </ParaGroup>
        
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_21"/>Gateway server</P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">vCPU: 4</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Memory: 8 GB</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Storage:
            <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul_ul">
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">Primary disk (vmdisk1): 100 GB</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">Data disk (vmdisk2): 75 GB</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">Swap disk (vmdisk3): 40 - 100 GB</P>
            </ParaGroup></P>
        </ParaGroup>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_22"/>DataServer - Classic</P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
            <!--topic/li--><!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">vCPU: 4</P>
                <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" listLabel="N" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">Even though increasing the number of vCPUs increases performance, the actual benefits depend on
                    whether the specific host is oversubscribed or not.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Memory: 16 GB</P>
                <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" listLabel="N">While the minimum value works under light-load condition, as the load increases, the data server
                    quickly starts using swap space. For high load situations, increasing RAM beyond 16 GB can benefit
                    performance. Monitoring swap usage can provide insight.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Storage:</P>
            <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul_ul">
                <!--topic/li--><!--p element nested in list at nest level 9--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">Primary disk (vmdisk1, SCSI 0:0): Default is 150 GB</P>
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 9--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2" listLabel="N" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">This virtual disk has an associated VMDK that contains the IBM StoredIQ operating code. Do not
                        change its size.</P>
                <!--p element nested in list at nest level 9--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2" listLabel="N" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">
                    <!--HAZARD STATEMENT--><Tbl tblDef="hazardstatement" columns="1"><Row type="header" fillColor=""><Cell columnSpan="remainder"><P paraDef="hazardstatement"><ListLabel><Image file="M:\build-tools\note-images/note.svg" top="-1mm"/></ListLabel>
					
					 Note</P></Cell></Row><Row><Cell><ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul_ul">
                        <!--topic/li--><P paraDef="typeofhazard">Attention</P>
                        <!--topic/li--><P paraDef="howtoavoid">If you delete the primary disk, you delete the operating system, and the IBM
                            StoredIQ software; the virtual machine might need to be scrapped.</P>
                    </ParaGroup></Cell></Row></Tbl></P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--p element nested in list at nest level 9--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">Data disk (vmdisk2, SCSI 0:1): Default is 2 TB</P>
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 9--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2" listLabel="N">This virtual disk can be resized according to expectations on the amount of harvest data to be
                        stored. For purposes of estimation, the index storage requirement for metadata is about 30 GB
                        per TB of managed source data. Full-text indexing requires an extra 170 GB per TB. Therefore,
                        the default data disk size is targeted for managing 10 TB of source information.</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--p element nested in list at nest level 9--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">Swap disk (vmdisk3, SCSI 0:2): Default is 40 GB</P>
                    <!--p element nested in list at nest level 9--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2" listLabel="N">When under load, the data server can use much RAM; therefore, having ample swap space is
                        prudent. The minimum swap size is equal to the amount of RAM configured for the virtual
                        machine. For best performance under load, place this disk on the highest speed data store
                        available to the host.</P>
                </ParaGroup>
        </ParaGroup>
        <P paraDef="body">The general size limits for a data server are 150 million objects or 500 defined volumes, whichever
            limit is reached first. Assuming an average object size of 200 KB equals about 30 TB of managed
            storage across 30 volumes of 5 million objects each, the index storage requirement for metadata on
            ~30 TB of storage that contains uncompressed general office documents is ~330 GB (11 GB per TB).
            Add 100 GB per TB of managed storage for full-text or snippet index. For example, to support 30 TB
            of storage that is indexed for metadata, you need 8 TB indexed for full-text search and extracted text
            (snippet cache) of 8 TB for auto-classification. A total of 1.9 TB of storage is required (metadata: 330
            GB, full-text: 800 GB, snippet cache: 800 GB).</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Data-server performance is impacted by the IOPS available from the storage subsystem. For each
            data server under maximum workload, at least 650 IOPS generally delivers acceptable performance.
            In the situations where there is a high load on the system, the IOPS that is used can reach up to 7000
            with main write operations.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_23"/>DataServer - Distributed</P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">vCPU: 4</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Memory: 16 GB</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Storage:</P>
            <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul_ul">
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">Primary disk (vmdisk1, SCSI 0:0): Default is 150 GB</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">Data disk (vmdisk2, SCSI 0:1): Default is 2 TB</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">Swap disk (vmdisk3, SCSI 0:2): Default is 40 GB</P>
            </ParaGroup>
        </ParaGroup>
        <P paraDef="body">If you deploy this type of data server, you must also deploy an Elasticsearch cluster with at least one
            node. If you deploy a cluster with more nodes, each of the Elasticsearch nodes must meet the listed
            requirements.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_24"/>Each Elasticsearch node</P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">vCPU: 1</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Memory: 32 GB</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Storage:</P>
            <!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul_ul">
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">Primary disk (vmdisk1): 100 GB</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">Data disk (vmdisk2): 1 TB</P>
            </ParaGroup>
        </ParaGroup>
        <P paraDef="body">The required memory depends on the index size that is handled by the data node. For a better
            performance, consider increasing the memory. The total memory available to the node must be
            distributed between the host operating system, the Elasticsearch java heap space, and the kernel file
            system caches. For example, if the system has 32 GB memory, 2 GB must be allocated for the host
            operating system, 15 GB for the java heap space, and the remaining 15 GB for the file system caches.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">The data disk (vmdisk2) can be resized according to expectations on the amount of harvest data to be
            stored.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=1 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title1"><MkDest id="#unique_25"/>Network and port requirements</P>
        <P paraDef="body">For proper communication, the IBM StoredIQ components must be able to connect to each other.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">You must enable network connectivity from the following locations:</P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">The data server IP address to the gateway IP address on port 11103</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">The gateway IP address to and from the application stack IP address on port 8765 and 5432</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Ports 80, 443, and 22 from the administrative workstation to the application stack and data server IP
                addresses</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Port 22 from the administrative workstation to the gateway IP address.</P>
        </ParaGroup>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_26"/>TCP: port ranges for the firewall</P>
        <P paraDef="body">To ensure the network access for desktop volumes, the following port ranges must be open through a
            firewall.</P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">21000-21004</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">21100-21101</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">21110-21130</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">21200-21204</P>
        </ParaGroup>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_27"/>Default open ports</P>
        <P paraDef="body">The following ports are open by default on the IBM StoredIQ.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_28"/>SSH port 22</P>
        <P paraDef="body">By default, port 22 is open on all IBM StoredIQ hosts. The port is used for Secure Shell
            (SSH) communication and allows remote administration access to the VM. In general,
            traffic is encrypted using password authentication. To add a layer of security, you can
            establish key-based authentication for passwordless SSH logins to any of the IBM
            StoredIQ nodes in your environment as described in <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/pages/sites/default/files/inline-files/$FILE/IBMSIQDeploymentConfigGuide76019_1.pdf#page=51">“Configuring SSH key-based authentication” on page
                45</HyperCmd>.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_29"/>Default open ports on the AppStack</P>
        <P paraDef="body">
            <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><Tbl tblDef="table" columns="2" width="100%" topRule="all" bottomRule="all" startRule="all" endRule="all">
                    <TblColumn width="1*"/>
                    <TblColumn width="1*"/>
                    <Row type="header">
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Port number</P></Cell>
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Protocol</P></Cell>
                        </Row>
                    <Row type="body">
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>22</P></Cell>
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                        </Row><Row type="body">
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>80</P></Cell>
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                        </Row><Row type="body">
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>443</P></Cell>
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                        </Row>
                </Tbl>
        </P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_30"/>Default open ports on the IBM StoredIQ data server</P>
        <P paraDef="body">
            <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><Tbl tblDef="table" columns="3" width="100%" topRule="all" bottomRule="all" startRule="all" endRule="all">
                    <TblColumn width="1*"/>
                    <TblColumn width="1*"/>
                    <TblColumn width="1*"/>
                    <Row type="header">
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Port number</P></Cell>
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Protocol</P></Cell>
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Service</P></Cell>
                        </Row>
                    <Row type="body">
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>22</P></Cell>
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>PROD-ssh</P></Cell>
                        </Row><Row type="body">
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>80</P></Cell>
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>PROD-web</P></Cell>
                        </Row><Row type="body">
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>443</P></Cell>
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>PROD-https (UI and Web Services APIs)</P></Cell>
                        </Row><Row type="body">
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>11103</P></Cell>
                            <Cell rowSpan="2" verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                            <Cell rowSpan="2" verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>PROD-transport (IBM StoredIQ transport services;
                                communication between the gateway and the data server)</P></Cell>
                        </Row><Row type="body">
                            <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>11104</P></Cell>
                        </Row>
                </Tbl>
        </P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_31"/>Enable or disable ports or services on the IBM StoredIQ data server</P>
        <P paraDef="body">To manage ports, you can use the /usr/local/storediq/bin/util/port_handler.pyc script with
            the appropriate parameter:</P>
        <P paraDef="body"><P paraDef="lines" whiteSpaceCollapse="N">python /usr/local/storediq/bin/util/port_handler.pyc -parameter</P></P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_32"/><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">-s</Font></P>
        <P paraDef="body">To list the current rules in iptables</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_33"/><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">-l</Font></P>
        <P paraDef="body">To list the supported services</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_34"/><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">-d port_number|'port_range'</Font></P>
        <P paraDef="body">To delete a port or a range of port numbers from iptables, for example:</P>
        <P paraDef="body"><P paraDef="lines" whiteSpaceCollapse="N">python /usr/local/storediq/bin/util/port_handler.pyc -d '21200:21299'</P></P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_35"/><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">-e 'service_name'</Font></P>
        <P paraDef="body">To enable a specific service, for example, to enable HTTPS services:</P>
        <P paraDef="body"><P paraDef="lines" whiteSpaceCollapse="N">python /usr/local/storediq/bin/util/port_handler.pyc -e 'PROD-https'</P></P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_36"/><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">-d 'service_name'</Font></P>
        <P paraDef="body">To disable a specific service, for example, to disable HTTPS services:</P>
        <P paraDef="body"><P paraDef="lines" whiteSpaceCollapse="N">python /usr/local/storediq/bin/util/port_handler.pyc -d 'PROD-https'</P></P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_37"/>Default open ports on the nodes in the Elasticsearch cluster</P>
        <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><Tbl tblDef="table" columns="3" width="100%" topRule="all" bottomRule="all" startRule="all" endRule="all">
                <TblColumn width="1*"/>
                <TblColumn width="1*"/>
                <TblColumn width="1*"/>
                <Row type="header">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Port number</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Protocol</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Service</P></Cell>
                    </Row>
                <Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>21</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>ftp</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>22</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>sshd</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>80</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P/></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>443</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P/></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>8888</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>SimpleHTTPServer (used for
                            copying the <Font fontDef="codeph">siqelasticsearch.yml</Font>
                            configuration file from the
                            Elasticsearch node to the data
                            server)</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>9200</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp6</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><!--p element nested in table at nest level 6--><P>docker-proxy (listening for REST
                            requests)</P><!--p element nested in table at nest level 6--><P>You can restrict access to this port by either enabling Search Guard
                                or by setting up a firewall. For more information, see <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/pages/sites/default/files/inline-files/$FILE/IBMSIQDeploymentConfigGuide76019_1.pdf#page=57">“Securing Elasticsearch cluster
                                    communication with Search Guard” on page 51</HyperCmd> or <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/pages/sites/default/files/inline-files/$FILE/IBMSIQDeploymentConfigGuide76019_1.pdf#page=58">“Restricting access to port 9200
                                    on Elasticsearch nodes” on page 52.</HyperCmd></P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>9300</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp6</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>docker-proxy (internode
                            communication)</P></Cell>
                    </Row>
            </Tbl>
        <P paraDef="body"/>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_38"/>Default open ports on the IBM StoredIQ gateway</P>
        <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><Tbl tblDef="table" columns="3" width="100%" topRule="all" bottomRule="all" startRule="all" endRule="all">
                <TblColumn width="1*"/>
                <TblColumn width="1*"/>
                <TblColumn width="1*"/>
                <Row type="header">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Port number</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Protocol</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Service</P></Cell>
                    </Row>
                <Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>22</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>PROD-ssh</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>80</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>PROD-web</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>443</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>PROD-https (UI and Web
                            Services APIs)</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>5432</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>PROD-postgres</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>5434</P></Cell>
                        <Cell rowSpan="6" verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>tcp</P></Cell>
                        <Cell rowSpan="6" verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>PROD-transport (IBM StoredIQ
                            transport services;
                            communication between the
                            gateway and the data server)</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>8765</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>7766</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>11102</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>11103</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>11104</P></Cell>
                    </Row>
            </Tbl>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_39"/>Supported chain and rules on the IBM StoredIQ gateway</P>
        <P paraDef="body">In iptables, the following firewall and chain rules are defined:</P>
        <P paraDef="body"><P paraDef="lines" whiteSpaceCollapse="N">'PROD-transport':['5434','8765','7766','11102','11103','11104'],<br/>            'PROD-https':['443'],'PROD-ssh':['22'],<br/>            'PROD-web':['80'],<br/>            'PROD-postgres':[’5432’]</P></P>
        <P paraDef="body"><P paraDef="lines" whiteSpaceCollapse="N">'desktop' service:<br/>            'PROD-broker':['21000'],<br/>            'PROD-collectionsvc':['21300:21399'],<br/>            'PROD-desktopupgrade':['21004'],<br/>            'PROD-objlistmgr':['21100:21199'],<br/>            'PROD-objlistsvc':['21200:21299'],<br/>            'PROD-registration':['21001'],<br/>            'PROD-session':['21002'],<br/>            'PROD-task':['21003'],</P></P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent task count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_40"/>Open ports for desktop client access to the data server</P>
        <!--Using default mapping of class - topic/section task/context  on element context to body paragraph --><P paraDef="body">To open ports for desktop client access to the data server on OVA deployed systems, follow these steps:
        </P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ol">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara step--><P paraDef="step" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">
                Log in to the data server as root and run this command:
                <P paraDef="lines" whiteSpaceCollapse="N">python /usr/local/storediq/bin/util/port_handler.pyc -e desktop</P>
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara step--><P paraDef="step">
                Run this command: <Font fontDef="codeph">iptables -L INPUT</Font>
                <P paraDef="info">In the output of the command, check the list position of the rule that is named PROD-reject, for
                    example, the 6th position on the list.</P>
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara step--><P paraDef="step">
                Run this command: <Font fontDef="codeph">iptables -A INPUT -j PROD-reject</Font>
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara step--><P paraDef="step">
                Run this command: <Font fontDef="codeph">iptables -D INPUT <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [i] id=--><Font fontDef="i">list_position</Font></Font>
                <P paraDef="info"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [i] id=--><Font fontDef="i">list_position</Font> is the position number of the PROD-reject rule that you determined in step 2.</P>
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara step--><P paraDef="step">
                Run the following command:
                <P paraDef="lines" whiteSpaceCollapse="N">python /usr/local/storediq/bin/util/port_handler.pyc -e desktop</P>
            </P>
        </ParaGroup>
        <!--Using default mapping of class - topic/section task/tasktroubleshooting  on element tasktroubleshooting to body paragraph --><P paraDef="body"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Tip:</Font> These steps are required only on an IBM StoredIQ OVA deployed system. The correct ports are open
            on an upgraded system.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=1 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title1"><MkDest id="#unique_41"/>Environment sizing guidelines</P>
        <P paraDef="body">To size an environment precisely, you must understand the factors such as harvest
            frequency, complexity of the source, and use case scenarios that drive application use
            and action execution.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">The general design guidelines for IBM StoredIQ are as follows:</P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">For data servers of the type DataServer - Classic: <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul_ul">
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">One data server for up to 30 TBs of data (which can vary based on the number
                        of volumes, objects per volume, and object types).</P>
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">Up to 500 volumes per data server.<!--p element nested in list at nest level 6--><!--makeListPara p--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">Tip: When you're sizing an environment
                            that includes Sharepoint data sources, keep in mind that volumes must be
                            defined at Sharepoint site collection level, not the Sharepoint server
                            level.</P></P>
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">Up to 150 million objects per data server.</P>
                </ParaGroup></P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">One gateway per 50 data servers.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">One application server.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">NFS is slightly faster than CIFS for metadata only, but assume CIFS/NFS even for
                this exercise.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Full-content processing of file (for example, .ZIP, .RAR, .GZ) and email archive
                (.PST, .NSF, .EMX) processing are slower as items must be extracted from the
                archives. If there is a significant number of these files in the file system and
                they are not excluded from content processing, the full-content processing rate can
                be too high. Until you have an initial index of the file system, you do not know how
                to weigh full-content processing of archives.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">An object/time metric is appropriate for metadata only NOT computing a hash, membership in the
                National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) or enumerating objects that are contained in
                archives. Converting it to a bytes/time metric is a function of the average object size and might vary
                tremendously. An average object size of 250 KB was used for the metric that is provided earlier.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">A bytes/time metric is appropriate for metadata-only computing a hash and full-content processing.
                The object per second rate can vary tremendously depending on the object type and sizes encountered.
                For example, processing an email or file archive is much more expensive than a PDF document.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Metadata-only not computing a hash, membership in the NIST list, or enumerating objects that are
                contained in archives is requesting only the file-attribute information from the NAS. Individual files are
                not opened and read. The processing rate is high, but that does not translate into a large amount of data
                that traverses a network between the NAS and data server. The bytes/time rate does not translate into
                bytes served by the NAS and sent over the network.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Metadata-only computing a hash, membership in the NIST list, or enumerating objects that are
                contained in archives opens and reads the contents of each file. The content of all requested files
                traverses the network between the NAS and data server. The maximum load that the data server can
                place on a NAS is metadata-only processing. It requires all file content to be read to compute a hash or
                enumerate objects that are contained in archives. The bytes/time rate translates into bytes served up
                by the NAS and network traffic that must be considered.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Full-content processing opens and reads the contents of each file to extract all text. The content of all
                requested files traverses the network between the NAS and data server. The processing time to
                enumerate archives, extract text, index words, and extract entities on the data server reduces the rate
                that data is requested from a NAS compared to metadata-only with full hash. The bytes/time rate
                translates into bytes served up by the NAS and network traffic that must be considered.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">The interrogator process count on the data server for "metadata only not reading all content indexing" is
                set to eight for optimal performance.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">The interrogator process count for all other processing that involves reading all content default setting
                is four per data server.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">The interrogator count can be viewed as the number of client connections that are made to a data
                source actively requesting data. It is important for capacity planning for the data source.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">The data servers are assumed to be "network close" to the NAS data sources. Network latency under 10
                ms with at least 1000 Mbps bandwidth is assumed (connected through local area network). The data
                servers need a low latency high-bandwidth connection to a NAS data source for acceptable indexing
                performance.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">The gateway and application stack can be located remotely from the data servers. Network connections
                with latency greater than 10 ms and bandwidth of at least 2+ Mbps are acceptable.</P>

        </ParaGroup>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_42"/>VMware requirements</P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">VMware vSphere v5.0 and fix packs or v6.0 and fix packs.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">VMware ESXi v5.0 and fix packs, v6.0 and fix packs, or v6.5 and fix packs.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">VMware virtual machine hardware version 8.0 or later. For more information, see
                        <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.vmware.com/support/pubs/">the VMware product documentation</HyperCmd>.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">The appropriate VMware license to enable the required processor cores and memory for the virtual
                machine.</P>
        </ParaGroup>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=1 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title1"><MkDest id="#unique_43"/>Stack-provisioning prerequisites</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Before a deployment, verify that you meet these prerequisites.</P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">At least one physical server with sufficient processor, RAM, and hard disk configuration for the planned
                management project.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">VMware ESX or ESXi on CD/DVD or USB drive.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">IP addresses, cables, and physical switch ports for at least the ESXi/ESX interface, one data server, one
                gateway server, and one application stack.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Network connectivity that is enabled from the following locations:
            <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul_ul">
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">The data server IP address to the gateway IP address on port 11103</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">The gateway IP address to and from the application stack IP address on port 8765 and 5432</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">Ports 80, 443, and 22 from the administrative workstation to the application stack and data server IP
                    addresses</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">Port 22 from the administrative workstation to the gateway IP address.</P>
            </ParaGroup></P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Network connectivity that is enabled from the data server IP address to any data sources to be
                harvested and managed.</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">A management station computer or notebook from where the load-management work is done.</P>
        </ParaGroup>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=1 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title1"><MkDest id="#unique_44"/>License usage metrics</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Using the IBM License Metric Tool, you can generate license consumption reports that count IBM
            StoredIQ license usage.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ is licensed by Resource Value Unit (RVU). RVU calculation is based on terabytes IBM
            StoredIQ.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">On the IBM StoredIQ application stack, a license program writes usage information to an IBM Software
            Licence Metric Tag (SLMT) file. This file has the extension .slmtag and can be read periodically by the IBM
            License Metric Tool (ILMT) after it has been configured to scan for these files. You can generate reports
            that summarize usage.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">By default, the license program retrieves the size of the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">All Data Objects</Font> infoset in terabytes once per day
            and writes this information to the /var/siq/ilmt/3cd1469042433ee7010fe09f661dc67b.slmtag
            file. The .slmtag file can store information up to a maximum file size of 1 MB, after which the file is
            archived and a new log file is created. A maximum of 10 log files are kept.˂</P>
        <P paraDef="body">The .slmtag file contains usage information in the following format, where new metric records are
            appended to the end of the file:</P>
        <P paraDef="lines" whiteSpaceCollapse="N"><br/>            &lt;SchemaVersion&gt;2.1.1&lt;/SchemaVersion&gt;<br/>            &lt;SoftwareIdentity&gt;<br/>                    &lt;PersistentId&gt;cb98e260a2a14872902578de1b8e2016&lt;/PersistentId&gt;<br/>                    &lt;Name&gt;IBM StoredIQ Data Assessment&lt;/Name&gt;<br/>                    &lt;InstanceId&gt;/var/siq/ilmt&lt;/InstanceId&gt;<br/>            &lt;/SoftwareIdentity&gt;<br/>            &lt;Metric logTime="2019-01-25T15:58:26+00:00"&gt;<br/>                    &lt;Type&gt;TERABYTE&lt;/Type&gt;<br/>                    &lt;SubType&gt;All Data Objects&lt;/SubType&gt;<br/>                    &lt;Value&gt;0.005&lt;/Value&gt;<br/>                    &lt;Period&gt;<br/>                            &lt;StartTime&gt;2019-01-25T15:58:26+00:00&lt;/StartTime&gt;<br/>                            &lt;EndTime&gt;2019-01-25T15:58:26+00:00&lt;/EndTime&gt;<br/>                    &lt;/Period&gt;<br/>            &lt;/Metric&gt;</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_45"/>Integration with IBM License Metric Tool</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Versions of IBM License Metric Tool (ILMT) that support IBM Software License Metric Tag (SLMT) can
            generate license consumption reports. An ILMT agent can scan in configurable intervals the file system
            for .slmtag files, collect information, and send it to the corresponding ILMT server. ILMT reports the
            number of terabytes managed by IBM StoredIQ. This number is to be used as input for the RVU License
            Conversion Table specified in the license information (li_languagecode file) that comes with IBM
            StoredIQ. On the application stack, you can find the license information in the License directory.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">For more information about using IBM License Metric Tool, see the <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/knowledgecenter/SS8JFY_9.2.0/com.ibm.lmt.doc/welcome/LMT_welcome.html">IBM License Metric Tool documentation</HyperCmd>.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=1 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title1"><MkDest id="#unique_46"/>Security</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Plan and implement specific security measures to protect the application and the data it manages,
            especially when you deploy IBM StoredIQ into sensitive environments.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ keeps your data secure through encryption, security hardening, and auditing.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_47"/>Federal Information Processing Standard (FIPS)</P>
        <P paraDef="body">FIPS is a standard recommended by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) and the
            US Federal Government. It ensures certain security standards are met for software or hardware
            components deployed at US government sites. Enabling FIPS ensures that the SSL/TLS engine that is
            compliant with the US Government recommendation is used. IBM StoredIQ supports FIPS Level 1.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Secure gateway communication can be enabled without FIPS. If FIPS is enabled, IBM StoredIQ uses FIPS
            compliant versions of OpenSSL.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_48"/>Secure communication and encryption of data in motion</P>
        <P paraDef="body">In a production environment, you should configure or install certificates on the AppStack
            to enable HTTPS communication and to enable encryption of data in motion between the
            browser and the AppStack. You can to this during installation and initial configuration
            or at any time afterward. For details, see <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/pages/sites/default/files/inline-files/$FILE/IBMSIQDeploymentConfigGuide76019_1.pdf#page=41">the instructions for configuring
            certificates</HyperCmd>.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">The gateway handles the communication between the data servers and the application stack.
            By default, the communication between the gateway, any data servers, and the AppStack is
            in plain text and is not encrypted. If your enterprise security policy mandates
            encryption of data in motion, enable secure gateway communication. In this case, secure
            gateway communication must be configured on all three IBM StoredIQ components. You can
            enable secure gateway communication during installation and initial configuration or at
            any time afterward. For details, see <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/pages/sites/default/files/inline-files/$FILE/IBMSIQDeploymentConfigGuide76019_1.pdf#page=60">“Managing the status of secure gateway communication”
                on page 54</HyperCmd>.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ then uses stunnel to ensure secure communication between the components. If your
            environment includes data servers of the type DataServer - Distributed, stunnel can also be used to
            encrypt the communication between the nodes within the Elasticsearch cluster but not for encrypting the
            communication between the data server and the Elasticsearch cluster.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">To secure the communication between the data server and the Elasticsearch cluster and the
            communication within the Elasticsearch cluster likewise, you can enable Search Guard.
            For more information, see <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/pages/sites/default/files/inline-files/$FILE/IBMSIQDeploymentConfigGuide76019_1.pdf#page=57">“Securing Elasticsearch cluster communication with
                Search Guard” on page 51</HyperCmd>. If you don't want to do that but still want to
            restrict client access to port 9200 on the Elasticsearch nodes, you can set up the
            firewall accordingly. For more information, see <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/pages/sites/default/files/inline-files/$FILE/IBMSIQDeploymentConfigGuide76019_1.pdf#page=58">“Restricting access to port 9200 on Elasticsearch
                nodes” on page 52</HyperCmd>.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">If FIPS is not enabled, the following cipher suites and encryption algorithm are used for data at rest:</P>
        <P paraDef="body">TLS_ECDHE_ECDSA_WITH_AES_128_GCM_SHA256</P>
        <P paraDef="body">TLS_ECDHE_RSA_WITH_AES_128_GCM_SHA256</P>
        <P paraDef="body">You can configure these cipher suites in the configuration files listed in <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/pages/sites/default/files/inline-files/$FILE/IBMSIQDeploymentConfigGuide76019_1.pdf#page=47">the list of key and certificate files</HyperCmd>. However,
            if you run the utilities for enabling stunnel, you might need to make the respective
            configuration changes again.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_49"/>Encryption of data at rest</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Starting with IBM StoredIQ version 7.6.0.15, the disk volume on which the Elasticsearch
            indexes are stored is encrypted by default. IBM StoredIQ uses Linux Unified Key Setup
            (LUKS) for disk encryption. For details about key management, see <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/pages/sites/default/files/inline-files/$FILE/IBMSIQDeploymentConfigGuide76019_1.pdf#page=47">“Key and certificate management” on page
            41</HyperCmd>.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Optionally, you can encrypt the application data on the IBM StoredIQ application stack.
            For more information, see <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/pages/sites/default/files/inline-files/$FILE/IBMSIQDeploymentConfigGuide76019_1.pdf#page=56">“Enabling encryption of IBM StoredIQ AppStack
                application data” on page 50</HyperCmd>.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_50"/>Network isolation</P>
        <P paraDef="body">If full-text harvesting and Step-up Analytics actions (cartridges) are applied, Elasticsearch indexes can
            contain potentially sensitive content. Therefore, you should deploy the Elasticsearch nodes in an isolated
            location on the network (for example, as an enclave or behind a firewall) that is properly secured
            according to the sensitivity of the data being harvested. Only the IBM StoredIQ application stack and data
            servers should be allowed to communicate with the Elasticsearch nodes.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Also, any data servers and the gateway should be deployed in an isolated network location to allow for
            communication with authorized clients only.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_51"/>Access control</P>
        <P paraDef="body">The following administrative accounts are required. The builder and siqadmin accounts are
            IBM StoredIQ-specific accounts. For more information about these accounts, see <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/pages/sites/default/files/inline-files/$FILE/IBMSIQDeploymentConfigGuide76019_1.pdf#page=23">“Default user accounts” on page 17</HyperCmd>.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_52"/><Font fontDef="codeph">root</Font> and builder accounts on the Elasticsearch cluster nodes</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Remote login for root can be disabled. However, local root login is required, either log in as root or
            use the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">su</Font> command to obtain root permissions temporarily.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">You set the passwords for the root and builder accounts during the configuration process when
            you start the VM for the first time. You can change these passwords anytime.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=3 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title3"><MkDest id="#unique_53"/><Font fontDef="codeph">siqadmin</Font> account on the AppStack</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Administration of the AppStack usually does not require direct root access. For day-to-day
            administration, the siqadmin account can be used.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">You set the password for the siqadmin account during the configuration process when you start the
            VM for the first time. You can change this password anytime.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent concept count=2 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title2"><MkDest id="#unique_54"/>Default user accounts</P>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ comes with a set of default user accounts.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">For security reasons, change the passwords for these default accounts after the
            installation is complete so that they are unique and different from the default values.
            The new password must be 8 to 64 characters long and must contain characters from at
            least three of these categories:</P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">Uppercase letters: A - Z</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Lowercase letters: a - z</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Digits: 0 - 9</P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Punctuation marks or special characters: . : = * ˆ / $ # _ + @ &amp; % -</P>
        </ParaGroup>
        <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><Tbl tblDef="table" columns="3" width="100%" topRule="all" bottomRule="all" startRule="all" endRule="all">
                <TblColumn width="1*"/>
                <TblColumn width="1*"/>
                <TblColumn width="1*"/>
                <Row type="header">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Account</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Default password</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Description</P></Cell>
                    </Row>
                <Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P><Font fontDef="codeph">admin</Font></P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P><Font fontDef="codeph">admin</Font></P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>Administrative account for accessing IBM StoredIQ Data Server. Use
                            this account for the initial setup of the data server and to create
                            further administrative accounts for routine administration. Change the
                            password in IBM StoredIQ Data Server under <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Administration &gt;
                                Configuration &gt; Manage users</Font>.</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P><Font fontDef="codeph">audituser</Font></P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P><Font fontDef="codeph">Passw0rd!</Font></P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><!--p element nested in table at nest level 5--><P>Account for accessing the audit database on the AppStack.</P><!--p element nested in table at nest level 5--><P>Change the password by running the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">change_audituser_password</Font>
                                script as siqadmin user on the AppStack.</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P><Font fontDef="codeph">builder</Font></P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P>None. Password is set during initial configuration.</P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><!--p element nested in table at nest level 5--><P>Account for setting up and configuring the Elasticsearch
                                cluster.</P><!--p element nested in table at nest level 5--><P>You can change the password by using the Linux <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">passwd</Font>
                                command.</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P><Font fontDef="codeph">reportuser</Font></P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P><Font fontDef="codeph">St0red1q</Font></P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><!--p element nested in table at nest level 5--><P>Account for accessing the report database on the AppStack.</P><!--p element nested in table at nest level 5--><P>Change the password by running the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">change_reportuser_password</Font>
                                script as siqadmin user on the AppStack.</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P><Font fontDef="codeph">siqadmin</Font></P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P><Font fontDef="codeph">Passw0rd!</Font></P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><!--p element nested in table at nest level 5--><P>Administrative account for managing the AppStack server. For more
                                information, see the administration guide.</P><!--p element nested in table at nest level 5--><P>With new installations, you are prompted for a new password during
                                the initial configuration of the AppStack. In updated deployments,
                                change the password by using the Linux <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">passwd</Font>
                            command.</P></Cell>
                    </Row><Row type="body">
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P><Font fontDef="codeph">superadmin</Font></P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><P><Font fontDef="codeph">admin</Font></P></Cell>
                        <Cell verticalTextAlign="middle"><!--p element nested in table at nest level 5--><P>Administrative account for accessing IBM StoredIQ Administrator
                                and IBM StoredIQ Data Server. Use this account for the initial setup
                                of IBM StoredIQ and to create further administrative accounts for
                                routine administration so that their actions can be audited.</P><!--p element nested in table at nest level 5--><P>Change the password in IBM StoredIQ Administrator: go to Users and
                                edit the superadmin account.</P><!--p element nested in table at nest level 5--><P>The superadmin account has access to all IBM StoredIQ applications on
                                the application stack. To switch applications, click the triangle
                                arrow icon and select the application that you want to access from
                                the list of the available applications.</P></Cell>
                    </Row>
            </Tbl>

    <!--DOC ignoring text 
    --><!--map/topicref --><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--MAP/TOPICREF (doc)unique_55--><!--topic/title parent concept count= outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title"><MkDest id="#unique_55"/>Deploying IBM StoredIQ</P>
        <P paraDef="body">IBM StoredIQ is a virtual appliance that you deploy and configure in a VMWare virtual host environment.</P>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent task count=1 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title1"><MkDest id="#unique_56"/>Deploying the virtual appliances</P>
        <!--PASS-THRU: context @class=- topic/section task/context --><P paraDef="body">Use VMware vSphere Client to deploy the virtual appliances to an ESX server.
                Deploy OVAs for the gateway, the data server, and the application stack, preferably
                in this order. If an Elasticsearch cluster is also being deployed, those OVAs must
                be deployed first.</P>
            <P paraDef="body">Ensure that all prerequisites for the deployment described in the planning section
                are met and that the required software packages are available on your local system
                before you start this task.</P>
            <P paraDef="body">Download the latest version of IBM StoredIQ from either IBM Fix Central or IBM
                Passport Advantage®. For information about the package names and part numbers and
                the links to the proper download locations, see the <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/pages/download-ibm-storediq-version-76019">download document</HyperCmd>.</P>
            <P paraDef="body">The number of Elasticsearch OVAs deployed depends on the planned size of your
                Elasticsearch cluster. The default setup is a three-node cluster. Each Elasticsearch
                node requires a separate OVA deployment.</P>
            <P paraDef="body">The number of data server OVAs deployed depends on the number of data servers needed.
                Each data server requires a separate OVA deployment.</P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ol">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara step--><P paraDef="step" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">
                Connect to the ESX server or vCenter server.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara step--><P paraDef="step">
                Open VMware vSphere Client.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara step--><P paraDef="step">
                Select <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">File &gt; Deploy OVF Template</Font>.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara step--><P paraDef="step">
                Within the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Deploy OVF Template</Font> wizard, complete these steps.
                <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ol_ol">
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">
                        Within the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Select source</Font> page, click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Local file</Font>, and then
                            browse to and select the appropriate OVF. Click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Next</Font>.
                    </P>
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                        Within the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Review details</Font> page, review the OVF template
                            details.
                    </P>
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                        These storage requirements are critical and will be used to select a
                            data store during deployment. Click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Next</Font> to proceed.
                    </P>
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                        Within the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Select name and folder</Font> page, enter a name for the
                            deployed template or use the default name. Click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Next</Font>.
                    </P>
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                        Within the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Select a resource</Font> page, select the resource pool
                            where the deployed OVF template runs. Click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Next</Font>.
                    </P>
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                        Within the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Select storage</Font> page, select a data store on which to
                            store the deployed OVF template files. Click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Next</Font>.
                    </P>
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                        Within the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Disk Format</Font> list, select the disk format to be
                            deployed. Note that although <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Thin Provision</Font> saves disk space, it
                            can negatively affect performance. If possible, select <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Thick
                                Provision Lazy Zeroed</Font>. Click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Next</Font>.
                    </P>
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                        Within the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Network Mapping</Font>, map the network to the appropriate
                            network. Click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Next</Font>.
                    </P>
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                        Within the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Ready to Complete</Font> page, review the deployment
                            settings. Click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Finish</Font> to complete the Deploy OVF Template.
                    </P>
                    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                        At this point, you can select the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Power on</Font> check box to turn on
                            the VM after deployment is complete.
                    </P>
                </ParaGroup>
                <P paraDef="info"><!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Important:</Font> If your IBM StoredIQ environment includes an Elasticsearch
                    cluster, do not select this option when you're deploying the data server OVA.
                    The Elasticsearch cluster setup must be complete before you run the data server
                    first-boot process.</P>
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara step--><P paraDef="step">
                Repeat steps 3 and 4 for each OVA.
            </P>
        </ParaGroup>
        <!--PASS-THRU: tasktroubleshooting @class=- topic/section task/tasktroubleshooting --><P paraDef="body">Configure the components of your IBM StoredIQ environment in this
                order:</P><ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ol">
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="orderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">Elasticsearch cluster (if applicable)</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="orderedlistitem1">Gateway</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="orderedlistitem1">One or more data servers</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="orderedlistitem1">Application stack</P>
            </ParaGroup>
    <!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><!--topic/title parent task count=1 outputclass=--><!--STARTSECTION $outputclass=[]--><P paraDef="topic_title1"><MkDest id="#unique_57"/>Deploying IBM StoredIQ on Microsoft Hyper-V</P>
        <!--PASS-THRU: context @class=- topic/section task/context -->
        <P paraDef="body">As an alternative to installing on an ESX server, the IBM StoredIQ gateway, data server,
            and application stack can be installed on Microsoft Hyper-V. This option is not
            supported for the Elasticsearch virtual appliance.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Installing IBM StoredIQ on Microsoft Hyper-V requires the use of third-party software.
            For the procedure described here, the following software prerequisites must be met:
            <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ul">
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">Microsoft Hyper-V Manager must be installed on a Windows system.</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">7-zip for Windows or tar for the Linux operating system must be available to
                    extract contents of the OVA.</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">7-zip for Windows or gunzip for the Linux operating system must be installed to
                    decompress the vmdk.gz file.</P>
                <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem1">Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter 3.0 (Windows) or qemu-img (Linux) or must be
                    installed to convert the files from VMWare .vmdk files to Hyper-V .vhdx
                    files.</P>
            </ParaGroup></P>
        <P paraDef="body">Microsoft Hyper-V does not support OVAs and OVFs. The virtual machine needs to be built
            manually.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Consider the following instructions a sample procedure. The instructions might differ
            depending on the version of the third-party software.</P>
        <P paraDef="body">Complete these steps for the gateway, the data server, and the AppStack:</P>
<ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ol">
    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara step--><P paraDef="step" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">
        Extract the vmdk file from the OVA.
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ol_ol">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">
                Download the OVA.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Extract the contents of the OVA by using 7-zip for Windows or tar for the Linux operating system.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Decompress the vmdk.gz archive by using 7-zip for Windows or gunzip for Linux.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Delete everything except the vmdk file when the OVA extraction is complete.
            </P>
        </ParaGroup>
    </P>
    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara step--><P paraDef="step">
        Convert the VMWare .vmdk file to a Microsoft Hyper-V .vhdx file.
        <!--p element nested in list at nest level 4--><P paraDef="info">For instructions about converting .vmdk files to .vhdx files, see the following links:</P>
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ol_ul">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">Use <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/previous-versions/windows/it-pro/windows-server-2012-R2-and-2012/dn874008(v=ws.11)?redirectedfrom=MSDN">Microsoft Virtual Machine
                                Converter</HyperCmd></P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara li--><P paraDef="unorderedlistitem2">Using <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-us/red_hat_enterprise_linux/5/html/virtualization/sect-virtualization-tips_and_tricks-using_qemu_img">qemu-img</HyperCmd></P>
        </ParaGroup>
    </P>
    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara step--><P paraDef="step">
        Build a virtual machine.
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ol_ol">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">
                Select <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">New Virtual Machine &gt; Next</Font> from Hyper-V Manager.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Enter the name of the virtual machine in the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Specify Name and Location</Font> window and click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Next</Font>.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Select <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Generation of the machine</Font> in the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Specify Generation</Font> window.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Enter the startup memory in the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Assign Memory</Font> window.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Select the correct network in the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Configure Network</Font> window and click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Next</Font>.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Select <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Use an existing virtual hard disk</Font> in the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Connect Virtual Hard Disk</Font> window. Search the disk
                    location, select one of the primary disks, and then click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Next</Font>.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Finish</Font>.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Repeat these previous steps for all IBM StoredIQ disks.
            </P>
        </ParaGroup>
    </P>
    <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara step--><P paraDef="step">
        Optional: Add disks.
        <ParaGroup paraGroupDef="ol_ol">
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep" numberValue="1" withPrevious="Y">
                Select a virtual machine in Microsoft Hyper-V Manager.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Select the settings for the virtual machine under <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Actions</Font>.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Select the IDE controller and highlight Hard Drive in the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Settings</Font> window.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Select Hard Drive and virtual hard disk and click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">New</Font>.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Next</Font> in the New Virtual Hard Disk wizard.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Select <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">VHDX</Font> in Choose Disk Format and then click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Next</Font>.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Select <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Dynamically expanding</Font> in Choose Disk Type and then click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Next</Font>.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Enter a name for the disk in the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Specify Name and Location</Font> window and the click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Next</Font>.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Select <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Create a new blank virtual hard disk</Font> and enter a size in the <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Configure Disk</Font> window and
                    then click <!--topic/ph hi-d found: [b] id=--><Font fontDef="b">Finish</Font>.
            </P>
            <!--topic/li--><!--makeListPara substep--><P paraDef="substep">
                Repeat this procedure for all additional disks.
            </P>
        </ParaGroup>
    </P>
</ParaGroup>
        <!--PASS-THRU: tasktroubleshooting @class=- topic/section task/tasktroubleshooting -->
        <P paraDef="body">Complete the installation process by following the instructions in <HyperCmd fontDef="ulink" openURL="https://www.ibm.com/support/pages/sites/default/files/inline-files/$FILE/IBMSIQDeploymentConfigGuide76019_1.pdf#page=28">“Configuring IBM StoredIQ” on page 22</HyperCmd>.</P>


    <!--DOC ignoring text 
--></MiramoXML>